[
  {
      "question": "Q1: 'OS' computer abbreviation usually means ?",
      "a": "Order of Significance",
      "b": "Open Software",
      "c": "Operating Software",
      "d": " Operating System",
      "ans": "ans4"
  },
  {
      "question": "Q2: '.MOV' extension refers usually to what kind of file ?",
      "a": "Image file",
      "b": "Animation/movie file",
      "c": "Audio file ",
      "d": " None of the above",
      "ans": "ans2"
  },
  {
      "question": "Q3: For which of the following disciplines is Nobel Prize awarded?",
      "a": "Physics and Chemistry ",
      "b": "Physiology or Medicine ",
      "c": "Literature, Peace and Economics",
      "d": "All of the above",
      "ans": "ans4"
  },
  {
      "question": "Q4: Filaria is caused by______",
      "a": "Bacteria",
      "b": "Mosquito",
      "c": "Protozoa",
      "d": "Virus ",
      "ans": "ans2"
  },
  {
      "question": "Q5: The programming languages are ___.",
      "a": " C++",
      "b": " Java",
      "c": " Python",
      "d": " All of the above",
      "ans": "ans4"
  },
  {
      "question": "Q6:Which of the following is the original creator of the C++ language?",
      "a": " Dennis Ritchie",
      "b": " Ken Thompson",
      "c": " Bjarne Stroustrup",
      "d": " Brian Kernighan",
      "ans": "ans3"
  },
  {
      "question": "Q7:Which city is known as 'Electronic City of India'?",
      "a": " Mumbai",
      "b": " Hyderabad",
      "c": " Guragon",
      "d": " Bangalore",
      "ans": "ans4"
  },
  {
      "question": "Q8:Golden Temple is situated in",
      "a": " New Delhi",
      "b": " Agra ",
      "c": " Amritsar",
      "d": "Mumbai",
      "ans": "ans3"
  },
  {
      "question": "Q9:The Indian to beat the computers in mathematical wizardry is",
      "a": " Ramanujam",
      "b": " Rina Panigrahi ",
      "c": " Raja Ramanna",
      "d": "Shakunthala Devi ",
      "ans": "ans4"
  },
  {
      "question": "Q10: The python programming language was designed by________.",
      "a": " Guido van Rossum",
      "b": " James Gosling",
      "c": " Dennis Ritchie ",
      "d": " None of the above",
      "ans": "ans1"
  },
  {
      "question": "Q11:Which of the following comment syntax is correct to create a single-line comment in the C++ program?",
      "a": " //Comment",
      "b": " /Comment/",
      "c": " Comment// ",
      "d": " None of the above",
      "ans": "ans1"
  },
  {
      "question": "Q12: Why we use programming languages.",
      "a": " For developing machines",
      "b": " For enable communication b/w humans and computers.",
      "c": " Both A and B ",
      "d": " None of the above",
      "ans": "ans2"
  },
  {
      "question": "Q13:Olympic Champion Neeraj Chopra broke his own national record in which tournament?",
      "a": " Diamond League",
      "b": " World Indoor Championship",
      "c": "  World Athletics Championships",
      "d": " Asian Games",
      "ans": "ans1"
  },
  {
      "question": "Q14:Who has become the third fastest Indian female runner in 200 meters race?",
      "a": " Shivani Prithvi",
      "b": "Dhanalakshmi",
      "c": "Aishwarya Pissay",
      "d": "Anushriya Gulati ",
      "ans": "ans2"
  },
  {
      "question": "Q15: How many states in India ?",
      "a": " 28",
      "b": " 29",
      "c": " 30",
      "d": " None of the above",
      "ans": "ans1"
  }
]